# Chenkai Weng

+1-224-307-3331 | ckweng@u.northwestern.edu | carlweng.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest lies in cryptography, with a focus on secure multi-party computation and zero-knowledge proofs. I have participated in projects related to the security of garbled circuits protocol, efficient generation of correlated oblivious transfer, private data analysis in healthcare systems and scalable interactive zero-knowledge proofs.

#### EDUCATION

Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

PhD in Computer Science; Advisor: Xiao Wang

Sept. 2019 - present

Xidian University

Xi'an, China

BSc in Information Security

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

### EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

Evanston, IL

Microsoft Research

May. 2021 - present

• Designing and Developing secure multi-party computation and differential privacy applications.

Research Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - May. 2021

- Designing zero-knowledge protocols for boolean and arithmetic circuits
- Protocol implementation and evaluation

Teaching Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Introduction to Cryptography

### Security Engineering Intern

Beijing, China

Alibaba Group

July 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Survey on secure multi-party computation techniques
- Implementing threshold encryption and digital signature schemes based on MPC
- Implementing private set intersection protocol and order-preserving encryption scheme

#### Publications

### Efficient Conversions for Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Applications to Machine Learning

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Xiang Xie, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang USENIX Security Symposium, 2021

#### Efficient and Affordable Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Circuits and Polynomials over Any Field

Kang Yang, Pratik Sarkar, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Wang

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021

# Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Boolean and Arithmetic Circuits

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang

IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland), 2021

# Developing High Performance Secure Multi-Party Computation Protocols in Healthcare: A Case Study of Patient Risk Stratification

Xiao Dong, David Randolph, Chenkai Weng, Abel Kho, Jennie Rogers, Xiao Wang AMIA Informatics Summit, 2021

#### Ferret: Fast Extension for coRRElated oT with small communication

Kang Yang, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Lan, Jiang Zhang, Xiao Wang

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2020

# Better Concrete Security for Half-Gates Garbling (in the Multi-Instance Setting)

Chun Guo, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang, Chenkai Weng, Yu Yu International Cryptology Conference (CRYPTO), 2020

## Software

## **EMP** library

- [EMP-TOOL] Float-point circuits, utility functions
- [EMP-OT] Correlated-OT based on VOLE (The Ferret protocol)
- [EMP-ZK] Implementation of zero-knowledge proof protocols for boolean and arithmetic circuits